So, what's a bit? And a bit is the smallest
那么 什么是比特？比特是信息的
unit of information. So suppose I tell you that there are
最小单位 因此 假设我告诉你
two boxes. There's a green box and a blue box, and
有两个盒子 一个绿盒和一个蓝盒
in one of those two boxes, there's a gold star. And
有一个盒中 有一个金色的星星 而且
it's equally likely to be in either the green box or
它在绿盒和蓝盒的几率是相等的
the blue box. One bit is the answer to one yes
一比特就是一次是或否
or no question. So if you ask one yes or no
问题的答案 所以 如果你询问是或否的
question, you ask, is the gold star in the green box,
问题 你问 金星是否在绿色盒子中？
then you get one bit back as the response. You get an
那么作为回应 你就会得到一个比特 你会得到一个
answer that's either yes or no. And when you learn which one it
回答为是或否 当你知道它到底是哪一个时
is, that's one bit of information that allows you to go from
这就是一个比特的信息 让你从
having two choices down to one choice and then you know, well, if
拥有两个选择到一个选择 那么你知道 嗯 如果
the answer was yes, the gold star's in the green box, that's
答案为是 金星是在绿盒中 这就是
the one you should open. So when we think about bits in computing,
你应该打开的那一个 当我们考虑计算中的比特时
we don't usually call them yes or no. We call them 0
我们通常不会称它们为是或否 我们称它们为 0 或 1
and 1. 0 more readily maps to no, and 1 to yes. So
0 更容易映射到否 1 为是 所以
I switched blue and green here. But we could
我在这里切换为蓝色和绿色 但我们可以
pick any two things. We could use green and blue.
随便选两件事情 我们可以使用绿色和蓝色
We could use yes or no. If we have two
我们可以用是或否 如果我们有两件
things And we can choose one of them. Knowing which
事情而且我们可以选择其中之一 了解选择
one to choose is one bit of information. So that's
哪一个就是是一个比特的信息 所以这就是
what one bit can do. It allows us to decide
一比特可以做的事 它使我们能够
between two things. For the ancient Greeks network, maybe that's
在两者之间做决定 对于古希腊网络 也许这就是
all it could transmit. There was either the no bit,
所有它可以传递的东西 可能没有比特
which said there weren't any enemies arriving. Or if there was a
说没有任何敌人到来 或者如果有一个
smoke signal, that was one bit saying, yes there is an enemy
烟雾信号 这就是一比特的信息 说是的 有敌人
arriving. So it's possible if it was only able to transmit that
到来 所以这是可能的 如果它仅能够传递这
1 message, that it only conveyed 1 bit of information. If all we
一条信息 它只是传达了一比特的信息 如果我们所有
can do is send bits, we can send either a 0 or
能做的就是发送比特 我们可以发送任何一个 0 或 1
a 1, or a yes or a no. But let's think of
或 是或否 但是让我们现在将其
it as 0 and 1s now. Can we send anything more interesting?
看作 0 和 1 我们可以发送更多有趣的东西吗？
Can we just send one thing? And it turns out that we can
我们只可以发送一件事情吗？事实证明 我们实际上
actually send everything that we want, just
能够发送我们想要的一切
using bits. So instead of just picking between
仅仅通过使用比特 因此 不是只在两个盒子之间挑选
two boxes, now let's suppose there are four
现在让我们假设有四个盒子
boxes. So let's say, there's, a purple box,
那么我们说 有一个紫色盒子
and there's a dark red box. So now there're four boxes. There's still only one
然后有一个暗红的盒子 所以现在是四个盒子 目前仍然只有一个
gold star. So can we figure out which box the gold star is in with just yes,
金星 那么 我们可以只通过是或否的问题来指出
no questions? Well one way to do that would be to ask
哪个盒子中有金星吗？有一种方法是提问
four questions, right? We could say is it in the green box?
四个问题 我们可以问 它是否在绿色盒子中？
We could ask is it in the purple box? We could ask
我们可以问 它是否在紫色盒子？ 我们可以问
is it in the blue box and as long as we know there is
它是否在蓝色盒子？只要我们知道这里
at least one gold star. We don't really need to ask if
至少有一个金星 我们并不需要提问
it's in the dark red box, because if we got no for all
它是否在暗红色盒子里 因为如果我们在所有
three of these well then we know the answer to that next question,
这三个问题中得到否的答案 那么我们就知道下一个问题
if we asked if it was in the red box, would be yes.
如果我们问是否在红色盒子中的答案将为 是
So here we needed up to three questions, to figure out which box the gold star
所以在这里我们需要多达三个问题 以确定金星在哪个盒子里
was in. Can we do better? So the question is, how many bits do we need to
我们可以做的更好吗？所以问题是 我们需要多少比特来
find the gold star? And remember each bit
找到金星？请记住每一比特
is the answer to one, yes or no question.
就是一个是或否问题的答案
And we have four possible boxes and the
我们有四个可能的盒子 而且
gold star could be any anyone of those four.
金星可能是在这四个盒子的任意一个里